Hello, English Litters.
你好，英语学习者们。
Welcome to EnglishPod.
欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
We're bringing you a great elementary podcast today.
今天我们为大家带来一期很棒的基础播客。
That's right.
没错。
And we're going to be teaching you how to order pizza.
我们要教大家如何点披萨。
Yeah, you know, pizza is one of my favorite foods and the favorite food of many people.
是啊，你知道，披萨是我最喜欢的食物之一，也是很多人喜欢的食物。
Exactly.
完全正确。
It's one of those common foods that you're at home and you want to order something to
这是一种很常见的食物，你在家想点东西吃的时候，
eat and the typical thing is pizza.
典型的选择就是披萨。
Yeah.
对。
And you know, there's some very special language that you've got to use.
而且你知道，有一些非常特殊的语言你必须用上。
You got to know this language when you want to order a pizza.
当你想点披萨时，你必须掌握这些语言。
Exactly.
没错。
So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time as a man is ordering pizza.
那么，让我们第一次听这段对话，一位男士正在点披萨。
Good evening.
晚上好。
Pizza house.
披萨屋。
This is Marty speaking.
我是Marty。
May I take your order?
可以为您点餐吗？
Yes.
是的。
I'd like a medium pizza with pepperoni, olives and extra cheese.
我想要一个中号披萨，加意大利辣香肠、橄榄和额外芝士。
We have a two for one special on large pizzas.
我们大号披萨有买一送一的特价。
Would you like a large pizza instead?
您要不要换成大号披萨？
Sure.
当然。
That sounds good.
听起来不错。
Great.
太好了。
Would you like your second pizza to be the same size as the first?
您想要第二个披萨和第一个一样大吗？
No.
不。
Make the second one with ham, pineapple and green peppers.
第二个加火腿、菠萝和青椒。
Oh, and make it thin crust.
哦，还有，做成薄底。
Okay.
好的。
Thin crust.
薄底。
Your total is 2150 and your order will arrive in 30 minutes or it's free.
您的总价是21.50美元，订单将在30分钟内送达，否则免费。
Perfect.
完美。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Bye.
再见。
I need your address.
我需要您的地址。
Okay.
好的。
So I guess he's not getting his pizza.
所以我猜他拿不到披萨了。
No.
不。
He forgot to give his address.
他忘了给地址。
That's a bit of a problem.
这有点麻烦。
Okay.
好的。
Let's take a look at some of the vocabulary in Language Takeaway.
让我们看看“语言要点”中的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
We've got some great pizza words for you today.
今天我们为大家准备了一些很棒的披萨词汇。
And the first one we have is a medium pizza.
第一个是“中号披萨”。
Medium pizza.
中号披萨。
So that's the size, right?
所以这是尺寸，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
Medium.
中号。
You can say medium or?
你可以说中号或者？
12 inch.
12英寸。
Usually a medium pizza is 12 inches.
通常中号披萨是12英寸。
Yeah.
对。
So you could say, I'd like a 12 inch pizza.
所以你可以说，我想要一个12英寸的披萨。
Okay.
好的。
For those of us who use centimeters, this would be more or less 30 centimeters.
对于使用厘米的人来说，这大约是30厘米。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
Let's take a look at the next size, a large pizza.
让我们看看下一个尺寸，大号披萨。
Large pizza.
大号披萨。
A large pizza.
一个大号披萨。
So it might also be called an 18 inch.
所以它也可能被称为18英寸。
An 18 inch pizza.
一个18英寸的披萨。
Or isn't it sometimes called a family size?
或者它有时不是叫家庭装吗？
Maybe.
也许吧。
Family size.
家庭装。
I guess it depends where you're ordering.
我想这取决于你在哪里点餐。
Yeah.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So large and medium pizzas.
所以是大号和中号披萨。
Now let's take a look at some of the ingredients.
现在让我们看看一些配料。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
We have pepperoni.
我们有意大利辣香肠。
Pepperoni.
意大利辣香肠。
This is the common ingredient in all pizza.
这是所有披萨中常见的配料。
It's my favorite.
这是我最喜欢的。
A pizza is not a pizza unless it has pepperoni.
没有意大利辣香肠的披萨就不算披萨。
Okay.
好的。
So pepperoni is a sausage, right?
所以意大利辣香肠是一种香肠，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
It's a little bit spicy.
它有点辣。
And they look like a- Like circles.
它们看起来像……像圆圈。
Red circles.
红色的圆圈。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Olives.
橄榄。
Olives are little black or green balls.
橄榄是黑色或绿色的小球。
Yes.
是的。
Little green or black balls.
绿色或黑色的小球。
You can also find them in a martini.
你也能在马提尼酒里找到它们。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
Yep.
是的。
It's very common for them to have...
它们很常见……
It's very common to have an...
很常见……
It's very common to have an olive in a martini.
马提尼酒里放橄榄很常见。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And he also ordered extra cheese.
他还点了额外芝士。
Extra cheese.
额外芝士。
That means more cheese.
意思是更多的芝士。
Extra.
额外。
All right.
好的。
Another ingredient.
另一种配料。
Ham.
火腿。
The meat of a pig.
猪肉。
Yeah.
对。
Ham.
火腿。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
And he also ordered another strange ingredient for a pizza.
他还点了一种披萨上奇怪的配料。
Pineapple.
菠萝。
Now, this is a fruit.
这是一种水果。
I know.
我知道。
So weird to put pineapple on a pizza.
把菠萝放在披萨上真奇怪。
Many people like pineapple on their pizza.
很多人喜欢在披萨上放菠萝。
It's a tropical fruit.
这是一种热带水果。
Yep.
是的。
Comes from Hawaii.
通常来自夏威夷。
Usually.
通常。
And it kind of looks like a little palm tree at the top.
它顶部看起来有点像小棕榈树。
Yeah.
对。
Like, yeah, the top of a pineapple looks like a tree.
就像，是的，菠萝的顶部看起来像一棵树。
So pineapple.
所以是菠萝。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
Now, the last description of a pizza.
现在，披萨的最后一个描述。
He ordered it with thin crust.
他点了薄底。
Thin crust.
薄底。
Now, we know thin is some...
我们知道“薄”是……
Skinny.
瘦的。
But crust.
但“底”呢？
What is crust?
“底”是什么？
It's the bread part of the pizza.
是披萨的面包部分。
The outside part.
外面的部分。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So that's the crust.
所以那就是饼底。
That's my favorite part of the pizza.
那是我最喜欢的披萨部分。
Thin crust or thick crust?
薄底还是厚底？
Thin crust.
薄底。
Yeah.
对。
Thin crust.
薄底。
And I just, I really love that bread part.
我就是，真的很喜欢那个面包部分。
It's so important to a good pizza.
它对好披萨来说太重要了。
Okay.
好的。
Well, you know, they also have the crust filled with cheese.
嗯，你知道，他们还有芝士填充的饼底。
I know.
我知道。
It's so wrong.
太不对了。
That's good, too.
那也不错。
No.
不。
All right.
好的。
Let's listen to our dialogue again and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一聊。
Good evening.
晚上好。
Pizza house.
披萨屋。
This is Marty speaking.
我是Marty。
May I take your order?
可以为您点餐吗？
Um, yes.
嗯，是的。
I'd like a medium pizza with pepperoni, olives, and extra cheese.
我想要一个中号披萨，加意大利辣香肠、橄榄和额外芝士。
We have a two for one special on large pizzas.
我们大号披萨有买一送一的特价。
Would you like a large pizza instead?
您要不要换成大号披萨？
Sure.
当然。
That sounds good.
听起来不错。
Great.
太好了。
Would you like your second pizza to be the same as the first?
您想要第二个披萨和第一个一样吗？
No.
不。
I'd like the second one with ham, pineapple, and green peppers.
我想要第二个加火腿、菠萝和青椒。
Oh, and make it thin crust.
哦，还有，做成薄底。
Okay.
好的。
Thin crust.
薄底。
Your total is $21.50 and your order will arrive in 30 minutes or it's free.
您的总价是21.50美元，订单将在30分钟内送达，否则免费。
Perfect.
完美。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Bye.
再见。
Sir, wait.
先生，等等。
I need your address.
我需要您的地址。
Okay.
好的。
Now we have some really polite language that you could use possibly with customers or with
现在我们有一些非常礼貌的语言，你可能会用于顾客或
clients.
客户。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Let's go to Fluency Builder.
我们去流利度训练环节吧。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Okay.
好的。
My, all right.
嗯，好吧。
The first phrase we have, um, I think is my favorite.
我们第一个短语，嗯，我觉得是我最喜欢的。
This is the way that Marty answered the phone, right?
这就是马蒂接电话的方式，对吧？
He said, this is Marty speaking.
他说，我是马蒂。
This is Marty speaking.
我是马蒂。
Now why is this so important?
为什么这这么重要呢？
Because a lot of people, when they answer the phone say, I'm Erica.
因为很多人接电话时会说，我是艾丽卡。
Like hello, I'm Erica, which is not what English people say.
比如你好，我是艾丽卡，这不是英语人士的说法。
We always say Erica speaking.
我们总是说艾丽卡在说话。
This is Erica speaking.
我是艾丽卡在说话。
Exactly.
没错。
So guys, remember this.
所以大家，记住这个。
You'll sound really, really great when you use this on the phone.
你在电话里用这个说法会听起来非常非常好。
This is Marty speaking.
我是马蒂在说话。
Exactly.
没错。
This is Marty.
我是马蒂。
Well, don't use Marty.
嗯，别用马蒂。
Use your name.
用你自己的名字。
All right.
好的。
Then you also mentioned a two for one special.
然后你还提到了一个买一送一特价。
Two for one special.
买一送一特价。
A two for one special.
一个买一送一特价。
So that means you're getting two pizzas, right?
所以这意味着你得到两个披萨，对吧？
For the price of one.
以一个的价格。
And a special is just a special promotion.
而特价就是特别促销。
A special price.
特价价格。
Special price.
Yes.
是的。
Two for one special.
买一送一特价。
All right.
好的。
Now a very easy phrase.
现在一个很简单的短语。
Would you like?
你想要吗？
Now this is a great way to offer something.
这是一种很好的提供东西的方式。
It's a more polite way of asking, do you want?
这是一种更礼貌的问法，相当于“你想要吗？”
Do you want?
你想要吗？
Do you want is okay.
“你想要吗”是可以的。
Yeah, it's fine.
是的，没问题。
But it's less polite than would you like?
但不如“你想要吗？”礼貌。
Exactly.
没错。
Whenever you offer something, would you like a cup of coffee?
当你提供东西时，比如“你想要一杯咖啡吗？”
Would you like to sit down?
“你想坐下吗？”
Okay.
好的。
So would you like?
所以“你想要吗？”
Let's listen to our dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk about
让我们最后一次听对话，然后回来聊聊
pizza from a pizza expert.
来自披萨专家的披萨。
Good evening.
晚上好。
Pizza house.
披萨屋。
This is Marty speaking.
我是马蒂。
May I take your order?
我可以为您点餐吗？
Yes.
是的。
I'd like a medium pizza.
我想要一个中号披萨。
Would you like a medium pizza with pepperoni, olives and extra cheese?
您想要一个中号披萨，加意大利辣香肠、橄榄和额外芝士吗？
We have a two for one special on large pizzas.
我们有大号披萨买一送一的特惠。
Would you like a large pizza instead?
您想要换成大号披萨吗？
Sure.
当然。
That sounds good.
听起来不错。
Great.
太好了。
Would you like your second pizza to be the same size as the first?
您想要第二个披萨和第一个一样大吗？
No.
不。
Make the second one with ham, pineapple and green peppers.
第二个加火腿、菠萝和青椒。
Oh, and make it thin crust.
哦，还要薄底。
Okay.
好的。
Thin crust.
薄底。
Your total is 2150 and your order will arrive in 30 minutes or it's free.
您的总价是2150，订单将在30分钟内送达，否则免费。
Perfect.
完美。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Thank you for addressing.
谢谢您的接听。
All right, we're back and we are here with our pizza expert, who else but Marco from
好了，我们回来了，和我们的披萨专家在一起，除了马可还能是谁呢？
ItalianPod.
Hi, everyone.
大家好。
Marco Two, right?
你是Marco二号，对吧？
Marco One.
我是Marco一号。
I am Marco Zero.
我是Marco零号。
He is Marco One.
他是Marco一号。
We've come to an agreement.
我们达成了一致。
So zero.
所以零号。
What's the deal about this?
这到底是怎么回事？
Well, we're talking about pizza today and we wanted to know what's your opinion since
嗯，我们今天在聊披萨，想知道你的看法，因为
pizza comes from Italy, right?
披萨来自意大利，对吧？
Well, thanks for the question.
嗯，谢谢你的提问。
First, the Marco Zero.
首先，我是Marco零号。
Is my mic working?
我的麦克风好用吗？
Yes.
是的。
It should be.
应该没问题。
Okay.
好的。
So, the problem with pizza is that, yes, it comes from Italy.
所以，披萨的问题在于，是的，它来自意大利。
Originated, the story goes, you know, the princess, the queen Margarita.
起源嘛，故事是这样的，你知道，公主，玛格丽特女王。
But the problem is that now this confusion worldwide, pizza and pizza hat, American pizza,
但问题是现在全世界都搞混了，披萨和披萨帽、美式披萨、
Italian pizza, that is not the same thing.
意大利披萨，这根本不是一回事。
It's not the same.
不一样。
Okay.
好的。
So, pizza hat is an Italian pizza.
所以，披萨帽就是意大利披萨。
No.
不。
So, okay, here it goes.
好吧，听我说。
Italians, a little bit of, Italians make food, but they're not good at branding it.
意大利人，有点，意大利人做食物，但不擅长品牌化。
Okay.
好的。
Americans, they're very good at branding the food.
美国人，他们很擅长给食物做品牌。
So they have Starbucks and pizza hat and blah, blah, blah.
所以他们有星巴克、披萨帽等等等等。
The problem is that since they have to brand it, they don't change the name.
问题在于，因为他们要做品牌，所以不换名字。
So they do this pizza hat that is totally different from Italian pizza.
所以他们做的这个披萨帽跟意大利披萨完全不同。
How is it different?
有什么不同？
Have you ever seen the two of them?
你见过这两种吗？
Have you ever compared them?
你比较过吗？
Yeah, yeah, they are very different.
是的，是的，它们非常不同。
That's true.
确实如此。
So, okay, can you put pineapple and ham on a pizza?
那么，好吧，你能在披萨上放菠萝和火腿吗？
Technically you could.
技术上来说可以。
Like it's possible.
说得好像真有可能似的。
As long as you call it Hawaiian, you can put pineapple in everything, I guess.
只要叫它夏威夷披萨，我觉得什么都能加菠萝。
But the problem, what I'm trying to say is that, okay, Italian pizza is, you know, you
但问题在于，我想说的是，好吧，意大利披萨呢，你知道，就是
have the flour, the pasta, the crust, the tomato sauce, and then the mozzarella cheese,
有面粉、面团、饼底、番茄酱，还有马苏里拉奶酪，
and that's the basic, and then you can build on top of it with some variations.
这是基础，然后你可以在此基础上加一些变化。
American pizza is basically take everything that you have on the table and put it on it.
美式披萨基本上就是把桌上所有东西都堆上去。
That's the main difference.
这就是主要区别。
But I'm not saying I'm against American pizza.
但我不是说我不喜欢美式披萨。
I'm saying that you just should change the name to another thing.
我是说你应该给它换个名字。
What do you suggest we should call it?
那你建议我们叫它什么？
Zipa.
齐帕。
It's close enough.
差不多嘛。
Close enough, yeah.
差不多，是啊。
But maybe you need like an A, like a Zipa.
但也许得加个A，比如齐帕A。
A Zipa.
齐帕A。
To indicate that it's American.
表示它是美式的。
A for America.
A代表美国。
Maybe.
也许吧。
A dot Zipa.
A点齐帕。
A dot Zipa dot com.
A点齐帕点com。
Can I have A Zipa?
能来一份齐帕A吗？
So Margo, I know that you are very much against
所以玛戈，我知道你非常反对
having Pizza Hut pizza.
吃必胜客的披萨。
I like it as an exotic experience because I like the fact that it's so much stuff in
我喜欢它作为一种异国体验，因为我喜欢它里面东西太多，
it that you cannot even tell the difference between the ingredients.
你甚至分不清食材的区别。
You know, they have the super mega supreme.
你知道，他们有超级至尊披萨。
Super supreme.
超级至尊。
With cheese in the crust.
饼边里还有奶酪。
I don't even know what's inside.
我甚至不知道里面有什么。
It's great.
太棒了。
It's like there's a part in my mouth and everybody's invited.
就像我的嘴里有个派对，所有人都被邀请了。
That's for me the feeling of American pizza.
这就是我对美式披萨的感觉。
Another interesting thing when we were eating pizza with Marco is that he noticed the way
另一个有趣的事是，当我们和马可一起吃披萨时，他注意到了
that people from different countries eat pizza.
不同国家的人吃披萨的方式。
That's right.
没错。
Italian people fold their pizza.
意大利人会把披萨折起来吃。
We do fold.
我们确实会折。
And another thing is that we have a whole pizza.
还有一件事，我们点的是整张披萨。
Like if I order one pizza, it's not like I share, everybody has one slice of it.
比如我点一张披萨，不是大家分着吃，每人只拿一片。
We order one pizza, you order your pizza, she order her pizza and so on.
我们点一张披萨，你点你的披萨，她点她的披萨，以此类推。
Pizza is personal.
披萨是个人的。
Pizza is a person.
披萨是个人（的专属）。
Don't mess with my pizza, Marco Zero.
别碰我的披萨，马可·零。
All right, well, this whole pizza discussion, let's see what our listeners have to say about
好了，关于披萨的讨论，我们来看看听众们怎么说
it.
吧。
I know that we have listeners from all over the world and what do they do with their pizzas?
我知道我们有来自世界各地的听众，他们怎么处理披萨呢？
Yes.
是的。
Or their zippas.
或者他们的“披萨”（发音变体）。
或者他们的“披萨”。
What do you like on your pizza?
你喜欢在披萨上放什么？
Exactly.
没错。
For example, how high do you want the crust to be?
比如，你希望饼边有多高？
Thin.
薄。
How high?
多高？
Thin.
薄。
How thin you want your crust to be?
你希望饼边有多薄？
I know that, for example, in some countries they put ketchup on their pizza.
我知道，比如有些国家会在披萨上放番茄酱。
I know once I was eating, I had a Japanese friend who ordered a pizza from Pizza Hut
我记得有一次吃饭，有个日本朋友从必胜客点了披萨，
and the pizza had the pineapple and other stuff on it and then she took out like ketchup
披萨上有菠萝和其他配料，然后她拿出番茄酱
and mayonnaise and she got like wild.
和蛋黄酱，像疯了一样往上加。
Although I must tell you, I like Tabasco on my pizza and I know that's wrong.
虽然我得承认，我喜欢在披萨上放塔巴斯科辣酱，我知道这不对。
I know.
我知道。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
But I like it.
但我喜欢。
You do what you have to do, Erika.
你按自己的方式做吧，埃里卡。
And history will judge you for that.
历史会为此审判你的。
Alright we better go.
好了，我们得走了。
We're out of time and before Marco has a heart attack or an aneurysm or something, we're
时间到了，在马可心脏病发作或动脉瘤之类之前，我们
making him angry here.
把他惹火了。
And if you have any questions for us and also for Marco because I'm sure he's going to be
如果你们有任何问题想问我们，还有马可，因为我肯定他会
commenting on this aspect.
评论这方面。
Sure.
当然。
So go to our comment section at EnglishPod.com.
所以去我们 EnglishPod.com 的评论区吧。
And Marco and I, Marco Zero and I are always there to answer your questions.
马可和我，马可·零和我，随时在那里回答你们的问题。
Alright everyone.
好了，各位。
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
Goodbye.
再见。
Ciao.
你好。